Hi, I'm **Luis Herrero Jimenez**. For over a decade, I have successfully translated **user needs** and **business goals** into user-centric design **solutions** at start-ups and scale-ups.

Thanks to my strong **process management** and communication skills, I **creatively lead** every stage of the design process, with a proven track **record of success**.

Work Experience

Tewke · Lead Motion Designer

June 2024 - Now

An iOT company, <u>Tewke</u> specialises in smart home automation and energy efficiency to reduce the environmental impact of residential properties.

Leading the visual design of the product, with special care to **motion** to enable a more engaging and memorable experience reducing complexity.

Mews · Senior Product Designer

Aug 2022 - Feb 2023

In the hospitality SaaS landscape, <u>Mews</u> provides a cloud-based solution to simplify and automate all operations for modern hoteliers and guests.

Prototyped and designed interaction processes aligned with business requirements to achieve strategic goals for **customer acquisition**.

Using a **user-centric** approach, I improved several features functionality and performance, using metrics to measure **user disengagement goals**.

Axonista · Lead Product Designer

Feb 2022 - Jul 2022

Covering B2B and B2C, <u>Axonista</u> is a video solution company that helps media companies and brands to deliver exceptional audience experiences.

Led UI/UX and engineer teams using agile workflows to launch **QVC+**, a brand new platform aligned to client's product strategy.

Prioritised **roadmap** to align the product needs with the business strategy to ensure a **successful launch** within a three-month timeframe.

Plex · Visual / Product Designer

Jul 2014 - Nov 2021

<u>Plex</u> is a personal media and AVOD streaming SaaS company that combines personal Media management with streaming services.

Owned design direction and implementation for **Mobile** and **TV** platforms, bringing excellent **visuals** and **functional** craft to maintain and evolve a **delightful** user-centric digital experience.

Working closely with **developers**, I created **Chroma**, Plex Design System to improve the design workflow and create a coherent user experience across multiple platforms and devices.

Education

Small screens, Big changes

Mobile App Design Workshop with Karen McGrane and Josh Clark

Multimedia App Development & Design

HNC - IES Clara del Rey, Madrid, Spain

English Philology

University Degree - Complutense University of Madrid, Spain



SHOWPAL TV

formerly iShows

0 0 *

Designer and co-founder of **Showpal**, an iOS app that helps users keep track of their TV Shows.

It is powered by a **gesture-driven** interface that provides a smooth, easy-to-use experience with high **customization**.

- More than 420K downloads
- More than 300K unique users
- Available in 16 languages
- User core base in USA, China, United Kingdom, Spain, and Germany

Don't forget to download the app here: https://bit.ly/showpal

Other Works

Mummies

2023

UI and Motion design work shots for Mummies **Core Animation** motion picture.

UX/UI Design Teacher

2017 - now

I've been sharing my **design journey** with students, covering workflows, patterns, fundamentals, and design systems at various schools including <u>UXER School</u>, <u>The Valley</u>, <u>K-School</u> and <u>EOI</u>

Skills

Visual Design · Interaction Design Wireframing · Motion Graphics Prototyping · Design Systems

Communication · Team Work Leadership · Mentoring · Ownership